Developer Ethan Ferrier

Cell: (503) 983-3730 Email: Fethanerrier@gmail.com Address: Redding, California

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-ferrier-891bb6155/

GitHub: https://github.com/F-Ethan Portfolio: https://ethanferrier.com

Personal Summary

A motivated and creative full stack developer with the technical skills to see any project through to the end. Specializes in light weight development through refinement and problem solving. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a full stack developer.

Languages / Frameworks

React *** Ionic **** Angular *** Python *** Django *** Flask **

 Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, JavaScript (JS), Ionic, TypeScript (TS), Es6, React, Angular, AJAX, Node, Express, Mongo dB, Mongoose, Passport, WebAPI, Python, Django, Flask, Beautiful Soup

Technologies

 VisualStudio2015, Sublime Text 3, Git, MVC, NPM, Bower, Atom, Dependency Injection, Heroku, mLab

Other Skills

Agile Methodologies, SCRUM, Unit Testing

Projects

That Food Truck

Frontend: https://github.com/bethel-school-of-technology/that-food-truck-blog-frontend

Backend: https://github.com/bethel-school-of-technology/that-food-truck-blog-backend

This is a project that I worked on with three other Bethel tech Students for our final graduation project. This is a React application built as a website for a food truck. We also built in a Blog that the admin of the website can use to keep their users up to date on the latest news. https://gracious-northcutt-ba993b.netlify.app

• Built with React, React-Router-Dom, Axios, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB

• Html, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NoSql, Cors,

My Portfolio -https://github.com/F-Ethan/MyPortfolio

This is a website I made to showcase my abilities. It is a simple React Project that uses axios to list all my projects on GitHub and allows users to download my resume. You can find my portfolio website at, https://www.ethanferrier.com

- Built with React, React-Router-Dom, Axios
- Html, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Web Tracker -https://github.com/F-Ethan/my app

This is an online application for tracking maintenance history, rental location and rental dates for an equipment rental company. http://pursuit.pythonanywhere.com

- Built in python with Django
- MySql, Html, CSS, JavaScript

Education

Bethel Tech Full Stack Web: December 2019 – August 2020

- Learned how to build web applications using Ionic, Angular, and eact.
 Acquired skills to program using javascript, and to make a database
 with MySql. Built a backend with Express and spent 20 hours a week
 programming and building web applications.
- Bethel School of Technology, powered by WozU, Apple's co-founder Steve Wozniak's coding bootcamp
- University
 https://www.newsweek.com/insights/the-top-coding-schools-of-2019/b
 ethel-school-technology

Harvard's CS50 Web Programing with Python and Javascript: January 2019 - May 2019

 Learned to Develop Web applications with python building with both Flask and Django and tying into MySql Databases. Spent 20 hours a week working on programing in Python

College Connections: September 2013 - May 2014

- Highschool diploma
- 30 college Credits

Stanford Summer Class: June 2013 - August 2013

• 12 college credits credits

Work History

Intern to the Operations Manager, Bethel school: September 2016 - May 2017

- Oversaw maintenance of Schools web application
- Reconciled 20 years of the school's student records from two databases and all their paper records.
- I streamlined the process using Excel and google sheets to sort through over 20,000 different Students and update all their pertinent information.
- Worked with developers to update schools web application and to add new features.

Computer Technician, Mikes Computer repair: June 2016 - August 2016

- Virus removal
- Screen repair
- New computer setup

Front End Manager, Food Maxx: *April 2014 - April 2017*

- In charge of up to twenty employees at one time
- Count checkers tills and safe and make sure they balance
- Deal with all unsatisfied customers